elm-chan.org 2004-10-11

# Privacy Policy

|  | About PIR |   
---|---|---  
  | 

President's Welcome  
  
Board of Directors  
  
Advisory Council  
  
PIR Policy  
  
Staff  
  
ICANN  
  
Legal Information and Terms of Use  

Privacy Policy  
  
|    
|  |   
  |    
|    
---|---|---  
| 

Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy last revised: July 11, 2003

Public Interest Registry respects your privacy. That's why we've adopted this Privacy Policy, which embodies our commitment to the protection of your privacy through adherence to fair electronic information practices. This Privacy Policy protects your privacy byinforming you about…

  * the types of personal data Public Interest Registry collects; 
  * how it collects this personal data; 
  * the specified, explicit and legitimate purposes for which it collects such data. 
  * the types of recipients to which it discloses personal data 
  * the choices and means by which individuals may access their personal data, and limit its use and further processing, including sharing with third parties. 

This policy also protects your privacy by assuring you that Public Interest Registry…

  * implements reasonable policies and procedures to ensure that the personal data collected , including the personal data collected as required by the ICANN contracts between PIR and ICANN, as well as between PIR and accredited registrars, is adequate, relevant and not excessive in relation to the purposes for which they are collected and/or for which they are further processed; 
  * does not further process personal data in a way incompatible with the purposes for which they were originally collected, except with the data subject's consent or by authority of law; 
  * uses reasonable measures to ensure that we have accurately and completely recorded the personal data provided and that for the data provided to PIR by accredited registrars, that we provide the mechanisms for the registrars to keep it up-to-date; 
  * implements reasonable policies and procedures to ensure that personal data is kept for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the data were collected or for which they are further processed; 
  * takes appropriate technical and organizational precautions to protect personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, alteration, destruction or disclosure, and against all other unlawful forms of processing. 

Domain Name Registration Information

Public Interest Registry is the registry operator for the .ORG top-level domain (TLD). As such, Public Interest Registry accepts domain name registrations only from ICANN accredited domain name registrars. Public Interest Registry does not accept domain name registrations directly from registrants. Please note that each registrar has its own policies and procedures.

If you have any questions about a particular domain-name registration, you should begin by contacting the registrant and registrar of record. Except for certain extraordinary circumstances, Public Interest Registry alters a record in the registry only at the request of the relevant and authorized registrar.

When you register a domain name through a registrar, the domain name, its associated nameservers, and other data are given to Public Interest Registry in order to make your chosen domain name a functional address on the Internet. Public Interest Registry discloses this data to TLD server administrators for the purpose of ensuring that the domain name operates as a functional address on the Internet. Public Interest Registry is bound by the .org Registry Agreement with ICANN.  
See <http://www.icann.org/tlds/agreements/org/>

Consistent with the .org Registry Agreement and the current rules and policies of ICANN, we may also disclose TLD zone files to other interested recipients, provided those recipients agree not to further process the TLD zone files for purposes incompatible with the purposes for which they were originally collected, including the transmission of unsolicited commercial e-mails. See [http://www.icann.org/tlds/agreements/org/registry-agmt-appn-22oct02.htm](http://www.icann.org/tlds/agreements/org/) (Appendix N to the .org Registry Agreement with ICANN)

Also, as required by the .org Registry Agreement, we make information about domain name registrants available to the general public via domain name registration database look-up (WHOIS) services. Please note that consistent with the current rules and policies for the Domain Name System set by ICANN, this information about registrants must remain available in the publicly accessible registration database. These services give users access to such data on a query-by-query basis. Qualified processors may also access such personal data on a bulk basis from ICANN accredited registrars, provided that the data subject, after being conspicuously informed of the bulk processing of his/her personal data, has not refused such processing, and provided that those processors agree, among other things, not to (1) use the personal data to enable or otherwise support the transmission of mass unsolicited commercial communications via e-mail, telephone or facsimile, or (2) process (including sell or redistribute) the personal data to third parties. For further information on bulk data please contact each registrar directly. PIR does not provide bulk data.

We are further required by the .org Registry Agreement to notify registrars of the purposes for which personal data submitted to us by the registrars is collected, the intended recipients (or categories of recipients) of such personal data, and the mechanism for access to and correction of such personal data. We are required to take reasonable steps to protect personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, alteration or destruction, and not to use or authorize the use of personal data in a way that is incompatible with the notice provided to registrars  
See: <http://www.icann.org/tlds/agreements/org/registry-agmt-appf-24oct02.htm>

Please note that every ICANN accredited registrar is bound by similar obligations to make personal data available to the general public via domain name registration database look-up (WHOIS) services operated by the registrars and to make such data available on a bulk basis to qualified processors. You may have the right to opt out of making your personal data available through bulk access. If you wish to opt out of bulk access to WHOIS data, please contact the registrar of your domain name.

Information We Collect on Our Web Sites

You are free to visit http://www.pir.org without identifying yourself. If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as your name and e-mail address. 

If you are interested in our services (other than registering a domain name, which must be done through an accredited registrar), you may be required to register with Public Interest Registry. When you register, we might request certain personal data, including your name, address, e-mail address, and other personal data, and, in addition to Web site registration. Public Interest Registry may, from time to time, request personal data for purposes such as the provision of customer service, service offerings, network management, surveys, and other exchanges of information, as long as such personal data is adequate, relevant and not excessive in relation to the purposes for which they are collected and for which they are further processed, and provided that this personal data is not further processed in a way incompatible with those purposes.

Log Files

Public Interest Registry gathers information about all users collectively, such as what areas of its sites users visit most frequently and what services users access most often. Public Interest Registry automatically logs session sources, and other data which tracks users' access to this site and the other channels and Public Interest Registry sites. We analyze these logs in order to understand aggregate user behavior as well as for system performance monitoring. These logs are analyzed for the overall, aggregate trends they reveal about our customers, not for the behaviors of individual users. Public Interest Registry may disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe the service to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

Cookies

A cookie is a small data file that certain Web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information that allows a Web site to track the pages you have visited. Public Interest Registry uses cookies to tell when a user is a repeat visitor and to let us know how the user found the Web site. They also allow us to automatically link users to their personalized accounts, enabling you to enter various services as a member and to visit member-restricted areas of the site without having to log in each time.

If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. Though some of the services require the use of cookies, visitors to our sites always have the option of disabling cookies via their browser preferences. You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. However, some of the services will not work if you have cookies disabled.

Children

Please note that we do not knowingly solicit information from children, and we do not knowingly market our products or services to children.

Sharing the Information We Collect on our Web Site

The information that you supply to Public Interest Registry through this site will never be given, sold, rented, loaned, or otherwise disclosed to any third parties outside of Public Interest Registry, except when we have your express permission, or under special circumstances, such as when it is necessary to comply with legal process or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Public Interest Registry, its customers, or the public.

We may share aggregated demographic information with our business partners and the press. This is not linked to any personal data that can identify any individual person.

Sharing Information with Our Partners

Our trusted processors (vendors, subcontractors, and other similar business partners) are responsible for processing some of the personal data that we receive on our behalf. These processors are not authorized to use such personal data for purposes beyond those specified by us.

Links and Third Party Collection

Except as otherwise expressly discussed in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the processing (e.g., collection, use and disclosure) of personal data we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your personal data to other parties, whether they are registrars or other Web sites throughout the Internet, different rules may apply to their processing of the personal data you disclose to them. Since we do not control the privacy policies of third parties or endorse their products or policies, you are subject to the privacy customs and policies of that third party. We encourage users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of every Web site that collects personal data. 

Security 

Public Interest Registry takes strong precautions to protect information. When you submit personal data via our Web sites, or when registrars submit specifics about the domain name registration, as required by the ICANN contracts, your personal data is protected both online and offline.

Furthermore, all of our users' personal data is access-restricted, and the servers on which we store personal data are kept in a secure environment.

Message Boards and Other Communications

Public Interest Registry is not responsible for maintaining as confidential any personal or other data posted by you on message boards hosted by our Web sites or otherwise communicated to this Web site and domain. Disclosing such personal data in this way makes this publicly available information unless expressly stipulated by Public Interest Registry.

Site and Service Updates

We may also send users site and service announcement updates. Users are not able to unsubscribe from these service announcements, which contain important information about the service. 

Updating Personal Data

If you are a domain name registrant and wish to update your domain account information, you should do so through the sponsoring registrar.

If you are another type of user, personal data changes (such as change of address), or if you no longer desire our service, you may contact us by sending a message to [privacy@pir.org](mailto:privacy@pir.org)

Contact Us

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us at: [privacy@pir.org](mailto:privacy@pir.org)

|  |   

|
